<speak xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis" xmlns:mstts="http://www.w3.org/2001/mstts" xmlns:emo="http://www.w3.org/2009/10/emotionml" version="1.0" xml:lang="en-US"><voice name="en-US-ChristopherNeural"><prosody rate="0%" pitch="0%">

<p>Welcome to the Applied Statistics For HCI seminar. </p>

<p><s>We focus on following statistical methods</s> 
<break/>Clustering and Classification, 







<break/>I will present you the following contents about Clustering, <break/> Introduction, <break/> motivation, <break/> Theoretical background and assumptions, <break/> 







INTRODUCTION to The Clustering, <break/> 








What are our goals in our life, <break/> 









The differences between  unSupervised and supervised Learning
, <break/>
, <break/>Unsupervised Learning, <break/>deals with unlabeled dataset , <break/> nevertheless, supervise Learning , <break/> deals with labeled dataset.

, <break/>, <break/>, <break/>








  Clustering is an unsupervised approach applied on unlabeled datasets.                             

, <break/> such as 
, <break/>     K-means, <break/>  Gaussian Mixture Models, <break/> and Agglomerative Clustering
, <break/> 
, <break/>









this gragh show us the result of appling K-means on unlabeled dataset
, <break/> 
, <break/> 
, <break/> 







it used to performs the gathering - clustering of unlabeled datasets into groups
, <break/> 
, <break/> 








Use cases, <break/> 
e.g. Marketing segmentation
, <break/> Image segmentation
, <break/> 





, <break/> 
, <break/> 
, <break/> 








Assumptions include
, <break/> 
 number of the Clusters k
, <break/> 
initial K-points centroids
, <break/> 




, <break/> 
, <break/> 
, <break/> 

 




the METHODOLOGY of K-means contain those five steps
, <break/> starting with Choosing the number of clusters "K".

, <break/> , <break/> , <break/> , 









and ending with Repeat Steps 3 and 4 continuously until the positions of the centroids are no longer changed.,

<break/> , <break/> 
 , <break/> 










we can use Elbow Method to find the best number of clusters,
 <break/> 







,
 <break/> 
 ,
 <break/> 
 ,
 <break/> 

 






but K-Means have some Disadvantages
, <break/> 
like Unable to deal with noisy data and outliers. 
, <break/> 










,
 <break/> 
 ,
 <break/> 
 ,
 <break/> 









 

the Implementation mission contains four parts, <break/> 

, <break/> , <break/> 









install the required python libraries
, <break/> , <break/> , <break/> 







Data cleaning steps and required data preparation
, <break/> , <break/> , <break/> 










then Reading the Dataset, <break/>Using Dependent variables, <break/> elbow method to find the optimal number of clusters,
 <break/> at end Visualising the clusters, <break/> 









last stage in k-means is Interpreting the results and all output elements.


</p>

</prosody></voice></speak>